Menu

Menu

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Spain searches for bodies after unprecedented flooding claims at least 158 lives](https://apnews.com/article/flash-floods-spain-valencia-climate-change-30c6ef59ddf27598c691c89d0ba41442)
    * [North Korea's long-range missile test signals its improved, potential capability to attack US](https://apnews.com/article/north-korea-missile-launch-377c07eac46ad41bda0d4445df6f51d5)
    * [Flood survivors say regional Spanish officials waited too long to warn them of the danger](https://apnews.com/article/spain-floods-what-went-wrong-33e385a9328f4040cb550441ffc85902)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Afternoon Wire
    
    Get caught up on what you may have missed throughout the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)
    * [Opponents use parental rights and anti-trans messages to fight abortion ballot measures](https://apnews.com/article/abortion-ballot-election-2024-transgender-e07e91d436744ad1634fe676dfbda687)
    * [Ping! Harris and Trump are blowing up your phones with political texts in campaign's last days](https://apnews.com/article/harris-trump-fundraising-texts-2024-campaign-6af8cde19cd5ba9a0bcbd536e45281d6)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Afternoon Wire
    
    Get caught up on what you may have missed throughout the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Speaker Mike Johnson is pulling closer to Trump to save the GOP's House majority](https://apnews.com/article/house-speaker-mike-johnson-majority-trump-election-65d7217e4541cd314849c9a0da2b0081)
    * [Nicky Jam withdraws endorsement of Donald Trump over comedian's 'garbage' comment about Puerto Rico](https://apnews.com/article/nicky-jam-donald-trump-endorsement-rescinded-1502ebc97adf28be8e22bb01d41a3e42)
    * [Inspired by Harris, many Black sorority and fraternity members are helping downballot races](https://apnews.com/article/divine-nine-black-sororities-fraternities-harris-connecticut-b2e58e1a6a1926f33628345248afdfc9)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Kamala Harris says Trump's comments on women 'are offensive to everybody'](https://apnews.com/article/harris-trump-election-f5903d49488ebc733d7ba5812b36f935)
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)
    * [Some 8,000 North Korean troops at Ukraine's border expected in combat soon, US says](https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-north-korea-troops-russia-ukraine-9ee96dc1d4f07ac0813c698e6873f96b)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Dodgers win World Series in 5 games, overcome 5-run deficit with help of errors to beat Yankees 7-6](https://apnews.com/article/world-series-dodgers-yankees-score-bd8e555b9bb5a321fff527e78e0ba637)
    * [Los Angeles sees city bus burned, store thefts and rowdy crowds after Dodgers win World Series](https://apnews.com/article/dodgers-world-series-crowds-bus-burned-arrests-a42e1c2b4a069cb6cf3c92572000ecbc)
    * [Saunas, reindeer and hockey: Stars and Panthers enjoy their time in Finland before 2-game series](https://apnews.com/article/nhl-finland-panthers-stars-1104097fc1939311f6e6935170b0f9da)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [AP Top 25 Poll Alerts
    
    Get email alerts for every college football Top 25 Poll release.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Sports Wire
    
    Your home base for in-depth reporting from the world of sports.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Beyoncé, Shaboozey and Post Malone topped country in 2024. How will Grammy voters respond?](https://apnews.com/article/beyonce-shaboozey-post-malone-2025-grammy-country-960555ab5de82ab630677677eb299a2e)
    * [Film academy adds handwritten ‘Pulp Fiction’ script, Miyazaki art, more to vast collection](https://apnews.com/article/academy-museum-tarantino-pulp-fiction-script-ca61c46b0919bf6cc534ec804e837ec4)
    * ['Saturday Night Live' taps comedian-actor Bill Burr and Charli XCX as hosts for after the election](https://apnews.com/article/bill-burr-snl-charlie-xcx-16807b9bbc6183ff0c9c000f467cdef2)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Inflation gauge closely watched by the Fed falls to lowest level since early 2021](https://apnews.com/article/inflation-prices-election-federal-reserve-rates-economy-e4ff4b6745ea1c8badd6a0502f372f25)
    * [Microsoft reports quarterly sales up 16% to $65.6 billion as investors ask if AI spending worth it](https://apnews.com/article/microsoft-earnings-ai-azure-copilot-7d11b44d6c0eecae11bdbb4327ae85f5)
    * [US applications for jobless benefits fall as layoffs remain at historically healthy levels](https://apnews.com/article/unemployment-benefits-jobless-claims-layoffs-labor-5df78bd6efc13a449b242df66b1dc57c)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [A spacecraft is on its way to a harmless asteroid slammed by NASA in a previous save-the-Earth test](https://apnews.com/article/hera-dimorphos-asteroid-impact-e716ac29b5b056861a995c0bf6342c2c)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [FACT FOCUS: A look at false and misleading claims surrounding the 2024 election](https://apnews.com/article/fact-check-misinformation-houston-rally-confrontation-99af1f80eb43d31966cae8e68dbc3415)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Trump repeated election lies in his interview with Joe Rogan. Here are the facts](https://apnews.com/article/trump-election-lies-rogan-interview-ballots-voting-c8c06eb608c1b1ae8ca0e93ec1022b02)
    * [Election officials are fighting a tsunami of voting conspiracy theories](https://apnews.com/article/election-2024-conspiracy-theories-misinformation-trump-musk-0e5a84b1d9e6cd63cd8ca22ee9900387)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Inactive voters on Michigan's rolls are misrepresented in suggestions of fraud](https://apnews.com/article/michigan-voter-rolls-fraud-fact-check-misinformation-3075e2cb1f7d69c27a5181a7e4ea7251)
    * [FACT FOCUS: A look at the false information around Hurricanes Helene and Milton](https://apnews.com/article/election-hurricanes-false-info-helene-milton-a4c2df2463b69c1f2e3eb6846e3b37ae)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Online posts make unfounded claims about a helicopter delivering aid in North Carolina](https://apnews.com/article/fact-check-helicopter-north-carolina-helene-d44fb04825337e8a7ca69e9f616621f7)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [A New Zealand city waves goodbye to its 'disturbing' giant hand sculpture that many came to love](https://apnews.com/article/quasi-giant-hand-wellington-sculpture-zealand-art-cfcd3599eda341b78741dcfcf519edbd)
    * [In a first since 1938, Des Moines, Iowa, kids will trick-or-treat on Halloween](https://apnews.com/article/beggars-night-des-moines-iowa-halloween-26710c8e3564d461b6868313f7f71425)
    * [He's the world's tallest teen — and is set to make college basketball history](https://apnews.com/article/worlds-tallest-teenager-d1c918fb54100a09a9c7db648c4ef71d)
    * [Rare dime bought by Ohio farm family and hidden for decades fetches $500,000 at auction](https://apnews.com/article/rare-dime-sold-c757327ec6540bf9e5132fdadc292886)
    * [Timothée Chalamet crashes his own look-alike contest after police shut down crowded event](https://apnews.com/article/timothee-chalamet-lookalike-dune-7acc6bda7612cb72eca31d2cc0106028)
    * [British chef Jamie Oliver urges followers to help solve the 'grate cheese robbery'](https://apnews.com/article/great-cheese-theft-london-cheddar-jamie-oliver-fbaf6d697cd5c7e00de1c95d33837d52)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Here's what you can learn from a mom of three who runs a half-marathon a day](https://apnews.com/article/helen-ryvar-wellness-running-58ecb121f4b83d5158e76d247f8da106)
    * [Winter depression is real and there are many ways to fight back](https://apnews.com/article/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-depression-winter-370fdaf388a65e5b31400f61d97d0575)
    * [Apple AirPods Pro's new hearing aid feature could help people face a problem they'd rather ignore](https://apnews.com/article/hearing-aids-airpods-apple-android-fsa-hsa-e0f243bcaff9b4c5b5068b546012b338)
    * [How to prepare your body and mind for the end of daylight saving time](https://apnews.com/article/time-change-fall-back-spring-forward-sleep-251e55ce23d25a490783a996915dbc22)
    * [Feeling stressed about the election? Here's what some are doing and what they say you can do too](https://apnews.com/article/2024-election-stress-meditation-mindfulness-anxiety-91550c0aa2c80da60f9f7d8220bcd702)
    * [Working Well: Seeking the elusive work-life balance, one step at a time](https://apnews.com/article/wellness-work-balance-stress-reduction-cancer-6f6e522e68d698315e0007bb34cb6ef2)

    Newsletters
    
    [AP News Alerts
    
    Keep your pulse on the news with breaking news alerts from The AP.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[Beyond the Story
    
    Executive Editor Julie Pace brings you behind the scenes of the AP newsroom.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[AP Top 25 Poll Alerts
    
    Get email alerts for every college football Top 25 Poll release.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[AP Top 25 Women's Basketball Poll Alerts
    
    Women's college basketball poll alerts and updates.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Native voters could swing US elections, but they're asking politicians: What have you done for us?](https://apnews.com/article/native-american-indigenous-voters-biden-trump-election-2024-6ca58c452dbd9a2af275dc1e31aacfc1)
    * [River and air pollution in India's capital pose a severe health threat to residents](https://apnews.com/article/india-river-air-pollution-6c0a891de6fd1ce35c5689831b9220bc)
    * [Boxing dreams live on in Congo's grassroots clubs 50 years after the 'Rumble in the Jungle'](https://apnews.com/article/congo-boxing-rumble-jungle-anniversary-c47a7dfdb6869e7106a5c63a650d81b5)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The World in Pictures
    
    Get The AP’s most compelling photographs sent directly to your inbox.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [The 'Black Insurrectionist' was actually white. The deception did not stop there](https://apnews.com/article/black-trump-kamala-harris-tim-walz-aca31c66fe5bfef1e8827581e7919ece)
    * [International court prosecutor who charged Netanyahu faces sexual misconduct accusation](https://apnews.com/article/war-crimes-international-criminal-court-sexual-misconduct-metoo-7519d876decb945aafc2215756df19b2)
    * [Thousands of children adopted by Americans are without citizenship. Congress is unwilling to act](https://apnews.com/article/adoption-citizenship-immigration-congress-0c71631786c35f7042ff99726e9dcd23)
    * [Right-wing influencers hyped anti-Ukraine videos made by a TV producer also funded by Russian media](https://apnews.com/article/social-media-influencers-ben-swann-russia-trump-jr-ukraine-zelenskyy-9d4281756246b94eda05c478f3dac203)
    * [Tech firms remove social media accounts of a Russian drone factory after an AP investigation](https://apnews.com/article/alabuga-russia-africa-ukraine-war-shahed-drones-bc175c4c98d752dc298c23434637417e)
    * [His country trained him to fight. Then he turned against it. More like him are doing the same](https://apnews.com/article/military-extremism-pentagon-veterans-terrorism-capitol-riot-jan-6-0c1fdd7b6b761e9c9e8556a9b9e45dc9)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Spain's horrific flooding another nasty hit in a fall where climate extremes just keep coming](https://apnews.com/article/spain-valencia-flooding-rain-climate-change-c77c6b49272420eea1d6324dd3016823)
    * [Fourth mass coral bleaching prompts UN emergency session at Colombia biodiversity summit](https://apnews.com/article/coral-un-bleaching-extinction-emergency-cop16-cali-colombia-ed4439fe10ac76a79443dbeab2c343c1)
    * ['All I can think about is hotter days.' Voter campaigns target Latinas worried about climate change](https://apnews.com/article/climate-change-election-2024-harris-trump-latinas-45b381be45eb4966636e13ffc4b3e025)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [McDonald's E. coli case count rises as federal officials inspect an onion grower](https://apnews.com/article/mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-quarter-pounder-a38666eaf2c38dccc99c00d72879928c)
    * [1st US case of bird flu in a pig raises concerns over potential human threat](https://apnews.com/article/bird-flu-pig-oregon-1f340a8f8c781e20478cbddabd2d9e18)
    * [Winter depression is real and there are many ways to fight back](https://apnews.com/article/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-depression-winter-370fdaf388a65e5b31400f61d97d0575)
    * [Teen fights kidney failure after eating McDonald's Quarter Pounders](https://apnews.com/article/mcdonalds-e-coli-food-poisoning-acb6d87f6182b42295d16625480525b0)
    * [People opt out of organ donation programs after reports of a man mistakenly declared dead](https://apnews.com/article/organ-donor-transplant-kentucky-8f42ad402445a91e981327abb009906c)
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Google Maps adds AI features to help users explore and navigate the world around them](https://apnews.com/article/google-maps-artificial-intelligence-entertainment-suggestions-bceb1ea762b3ac4a7a5a950fc4924756)
    * [New York semiconductor site picked for $825 million in funding](https://apnews.com/article/new-york-semiconductor-nanotech-lab-albany-42ee39316c32718c729e526354254724)
    * [Voting rights groups worry AI models are generating inaccurate and misleading responses in Spanish](https://apnews.com/article/ai-chatbots-chatgpt-falsehoods-spanish-latino-voters-d4ffabdc006a7c70eece3e28efa3de90)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Ex-Disney worker accused of hacking computer menus to add profanities, errors](https://apnews.com/article/disney-arrest-florida-orlando-theme-parks-0c075b6ff23f3d57fe44be6ea1a85407)
    * [Google Maps adds AI features to help users explore and navigate the world around them](https://apnews.com/article/google-maps-artificial-intelligence-entertainment-suggestions-bceb1ea762b3ac4a7a5a950fc4924756)
    * [Garlands and treats for beloved dogs in Nepal’s annual Kukur Puja festival](https://apnews.com/article/nepal-dog-festival-photos-diwali-kukur-puja-cec969221447238e5d1e8610178d76aa)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Then & Now: How immigration reshaped the look of a Minnesota farm town](https://apnews.com/article/immigration-policy-integration-minnesota-history-churches-business-soccer-5385d18481c901ee1faeec19c16ebf6d)
    * [In Amharic, Karen and Spanish, worship is like home for migrants in heartland town](https://apnews.com/article/immigration-policy-integration-religion-churches-minnesota-ethiopia-karen-8b2fdb67d7d8f82c0ed6dd2d0da1cb6d)
    * [Takeaways from AP's report on how immigration transformed a Minnesota farm town](https://apnews.com/article/2024-election-immigration-policy-integration-minnesota-education-economy-019135a73205346a310eb1595da88d86)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [World of Faith
    
    Comprehensive global coverage of how religion shapes our world.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Preocupados defensores de derechos electorales en EEUU por información de IA incorrecta en español](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-hispanos-inteligencia-artificial-elecciones-desinformacion-15ed781dd93aa56b29fa3797837ea22c)
    * [España busca más víctimas tras unas inundaciones históricas que dejaron al menos 158 muertos](https://apnews.com/article/espana-valencia-inundaciones-muertos-tormenta-84dab89c07dbc6cd1a7b9823802737fe)
    * [Los votantes tienen claro el mensaje sobre las elecciones de EEUU: el destino del país está en juego](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-democracia-harris-trump-a58245ed4337c961615a1b043b54ffae)
    * [La lucha por el control del Senado en EEUU se decide al límite; los gastos rompen récords](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-senado-trump-harris-democratas-republicanos-cdaa79148a3f9086dbd9572d544c85f8)
    * [Encuesta de AP-NORC: Estadounidenses se sienten ansiosos y frustrados por campaña presidencial](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-harris-trump-ansiedad-sondeo-apnorc-9c23c5be8dac38493ac33c1e6114fa71)
    * [EEUU dice que unos 8.000 soldados norcoreanos están en región rusa de Kursk](https://apnews.com/article/ucrania-soldados-norcoreanos-rusia-da31fd01b1e1a6a1c72abc57fb7c3628)

* ...

 Search Query Submit Search

Show Search

Submit Search 

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Spain searches for bodies after unprecedented flooding claims at least 158 lives](https://apnews.com/article/flash-floods-spain-valencia-climate-change-30c6ef59ddf27598c691c89d0ba41442)
    * [North Korea's long-range missile test signals its improved, potential capability to attack US](https://apnews.com/article/north-korea-missile-launch-377c07eac46ad41bda0d4445df6f51d5)
    * [Flood survivors say regional Spanish officials waited too long to warn them of the danger](https://apnews.com/article/spain-floods-what-went-wrong-33e385a9328f4040cb550441ffc85902)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Afternoon Wire
    
    Get caught up on what you may have missed throughout the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)
    * [Opponents use parental rights and anti-trans messages to fight abortion ballot measures](https://apnews.com/article/abortion-ballot-election-2024-transgender-e07e91d436744ad1634fe676dfbda687)
    * [Ping! Harris and Trump are blowing up your phones with political texts in campaign's last days](https://apnews.com/article/harris-trump-fundraising-texts-2024-campaign-6af8cde19cd5ba9a0bcbd536e45281d6)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Afternoon Wire
    
    Get caught up on what you may have missed throughout the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Speaker Mike Johnson is pulling closer to Trump to save the GOP's House majority](https://apnews.com/article/house-speaker-mike-johnson-majority-trump-election-65d7217e4541cd314849c9a0da2b0081)
    * [Nicky Jam withdraws endorsement of Donald Trump over comedian's 'garbage' comment about Puerto Rico](https://apnews.com/article/nicky-jam-donald-trump-endorsement-rescinded-1502ebc97adf28be8e22bb01d41a3e42)
    * [Inspired by Harris, many Black sorority and fraternity members are helping downballot races](https://apnews.com/article/divine-nine-black-sororities-fraternities-harris-connecticut-b2e58e1a6a1926f33628345248afdfc9)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Kamala Harris says Trump's comments on women 'are offensive to everybody'](https://apnews.com/article/harris-trump-election-f5903d49488ebc733d7ba5812b36f935)
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)
    * [Some 8,000 North Korean troops at Ukraine's border expected in combat soon, US says](https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-north-korea-troops-russia-ukraine-9ee96dc1d4f07ac0813c698e6873f96b)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Dodgers win World Series in 5 games, overcome 5-run deficit with help of errors to beat Yankees 7-6](https://apnews.com/article/world-series-dodgers-yankees-score-bd8e555b9bb5a321fff527e78e0ba637)
    * [Los Angeles sees city bus burned, store thefts and rowdy crowds after Dodgers win World Series](https://apnews.com/article/dodgers-world-series-crowds-bus-burned-arrests-a42e1c2b4a069cb6cf3c92572000ecbc)
    * [Saunas, reindeer and hockey: Stars and Panthers enjoy their time in Finland before 2-game series](https://apnews.com/article/nhl-finland-panthers-stars-1104097fc1939311f6e6935170b0f9da)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [AP Top 25 Poll Alerts
    
    Get email alerts for every college football Top 25 Poll release.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Sports Wire
    
    Your home base for in-depth reporting from the world of sports.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Beyoncé, Shaboozey and Post Malone topped country in 2024. How will Grammy voters respond?](https://apnews.com/article/beyonce-shaboozey-post-malone-2025-grammy-country-960555ab5de82ab630677677eb299a2e)
    * [Film academy adds handwritten ‘Pulp Fiction’ script, Miyazaki art, more to vast collection](https://apnews.com/article/academy-museum-tarantino-pulp-fiction-script-ca61c46b0919bf6cc534ec804e837ec4)
    * ['Saturday Night Live' taps comedian-actor Bill Burr and Charli XCX as hosts for after the election](https://apnews.com/article/bill-burr-snl-charlie-xcx-16807b9bbc6183ff0c9c000f467cdef2)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Inflation gauge closely watched by the Fed falls to lowest level since early 2021](https://apnews.com/article/inflation-prices-election-federal-reserve-rates-economy-e4ff4b6745ea1c8badd6a0502f372f25)
    * [Microsoft reports quarterly sales up 16% to $65.6 billion as investors ask if AI spending worth it](https://apnews.com/article/microsoft-earnings-ai-azure-copilot-7d11b44d6c0eecae11bdbb4327ae85f5)
    * [US applications for jobless benefits fall as layoffs remain at historically healthy levels](https://apnews.com/article/unemployment-benefits-jobless-claims-layoffs-labor-5df78bd6efc13a449b242df66b1dc57c)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [A spacecraft is on its way to a harmless asteroid slammed by NASA in a previous save-the-Earth test](https://apnews.com/article/hera-dimorphos-asteroid-impact-e716ac29b5b056861a995c0bf6342c2c)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [FACT FOCUS: A look at false and misleading claims surrounding the 2024 election](https://apnews.com/article/fact-check-misinformation-houston-rally-confrontation-99af1f80eb43d31966cae8e68dbc3415)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Trump repeated election lies in his interview with Joe Rogan. Here are the facts](https://apnews.com/article/trump-election-lies-rogan-interview-ballots-voting-c8c06eb608c1b1ae8ca0e93ec1022b02)
    * [Election officials are fighting a tsunami of voting conspiracy theories](https://apnews.com/article/election-2024-conspiracy-theories-misinformation-trump-musk-0e5a84b1d9e6cd63cd8ca22ee9900387)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Inactive voters on Michigan's rolls are misrepresented in suggestions of fraud](https://apnews.com/article/michigan-voter-rolls-fraud-fact-check-misinformation-3075e2cb1f7d69c27a5181a7e4ea7251)
    * [FACT FOCUS: A look at the false information around Hurricanes Helene and Milton](https://apnews.com/article/election-hurricanes-false-info-helene-milton-a4c2df2463b69c1f2e3eb6846e3b37ae)
    * [FACT FOCUS: Online posts make unfounded claims about a helicopter delivering aid in North Carolina](https://apnews.com/article/fact-check-helicopter-north-carolina-helene-d44fb04825337e8a7ca69e9f616621f7)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [A New Zealand city waves goodbye to its 'disturbing' giant hand sculpture that many came to love](https://apnews.com/article/quasi-giant-hand-wellington-sculpture-zealand-art-cfcd3599eda341b78741dcfcf519edbd)
    * [In a first since 1938, Des Moines, Iowa, kids will trick-or-treat on Halloween](https://apnews.com/article/beggars-night-des-moines-iowa-halloween-26710c8e3564d461b6868313f7f71425)
    * [He's the world's tallest teen — and is set to make college basketball history](https://apnews.com/article/worlds-tallest-teenager-d1c918fb54100a09a9c7db648c4ef71d)
    * [Rare dime bought by Ohio farm family and hidden for decades fetches $500,000 at auction](https://apnews.com/article/rare-dime-sold-c757327ec6540bf9e5132fdadc292886)
    * [Timothée Chalamet crashes his own look-alike contest after police shut down crowded event](https://apnews.com/article/timothee-chalamet-lookalike-dune-7acc6bda7612cb72eca31d2cc0106028)
    * [British chef Jamie Oliver urges followers to help solve the 'grate cheese robbery'](https://apnews.com/article/great-cheese-theft-london-cheddar-jamie-oliver-fbaf6d697cd5c7e00de1c95d33837d52)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Here's what you can learn from a mom of three who runs a half-marathon a day](https://apnews.com/article/helen-ryvar-wellness-running-58ecb121f4b83d5158e76d247f8da106)
    * [Winter depression is real and there are many ways to fight back](https://apnews.com/article/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-depression-winter-370fdaf388a65e5b31400f61d97d0575)
    * [Apple AirPods Pro's new hearing aid feature could help people face a problem they'd rather ignore](https://apnews.com/article/hearing-aids-airpods-apple-android-fsa-hsa-e0f243bcaff9b4c5b5068b546012b338)
    * [How to prepare your body and mind for the end of daylight saving time](https://apnews.com/article/time-change-fall-back-spring-forward-sleep-251e55ce23d25a490783a996915dbc22)
    * [Feeling stressed about the election? Here's what some are doing and what they say you can do too](https://apnews.com/article/2024-election-stress-meditation-mindfulness-anxiety-91550c0aa2c80da60f9f7d8220bcd702)
    * [Working Well: Seeking the elusive work-life balance, one step at a time](https://apnews.com/article/wellness-work-balance-stress-reduction-cancer-6f6e522e68d698315e0007bb34cb6ef2)

    Newsletters
    
    [AP News Alerts
    
    Keep your pulse on the news with breaking news alerts from The AP.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[The Morning Wire
    
    Our flagship newsletter breaks down the biggest headlines of the day.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[Ground Game
    
    Exclusive insights and key stories from the world of politics.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[Beyond the Story
    
    Executive Editor Julie Pace brings you behind the scenes of the AP newsroom.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[AP Top 25 Poll Alerts
    
    Get email alerts for every college football Top 25 Poll release.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)[AP Top 25 Women's Basketball Poll Alerts
    
    Women's college basketball poll alerts and updates.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Native voters could swing US elections, but they're asking politicians: What have you done for us?](https://apnews.com/article/native-american-indigenous-voters-biden-trump-election-2024-6ca58c452dbd9a2af275dc1e31aacfc1)
    * [River and air pollution in India's capital pose a severe health threat to residents](https://apnews.com/article/india-river-air-pollution-6c0a891de6fd1ce35c5689831b9220bc)
    * [Boxing dreams live on in Congo's grassroots clubs 50 years after the 'Rumble in the Jungle'](https://apnews.com/article/congo-boxing-rumble-jungle-anniversary-c47a7dfdb6869e7106a5c63a650d81b5)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [The World in Pictures
    
    Get The AP’s most compelling photographs sent directly to your inbox.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [The 'Black Insurrectionist' was actually white. The deception did not stop there](https://apnews.com/article/black-trump-kamala-harris-tim-walz-aca31c66fe5bfef1e8827581e7919ece)
    * [International court prosecutor who charged Netanyahu faces sexual misconduct accusation](https://apnews.com/article/war-crimes-international-criminal-court-sexual-misconduct-metoo-7519d876decb945aafc2215756df19b2)
    * [Thousands of children adopted by Americans are without citizenship. Congress is unwilling to act](https://apnews.com/article/adoption-citizenship-immigration-congress-0c71631786c35f7042ff99726e9dcd23)
    * [Right-wing influencers hyped anti-Ukraine videos made by a TV producer also funded by Russian media](https://apnews.com/article/social-media-influencers-ben-swann-russia-trump-jr-ukraine-zelenskyy-9d4281756246b94eda05c478f3dac203)
    * [Tech firms remove social media accounts of a Russian drone factory after an AP investigation](https://apnews.com/article/alabuga-russia-africa-ukraine-war-shahed-drones-bc175c4c98d752dc298c23434637417e)
    * [His country trained him to fight. Then he turned against it. More like him are doing the same](https://apnews.com/article/military-extremism-pentagon-veterans-terrorism-capitol-riot-jan-6-0c1fdd7b6b761e9c9e8556a9b9e45dc9)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Spain's horrific flooding another nasty hit in a fall where climate extremes just keep coming](https://apnews.com/article/spain-valencia-flooding-rain-climate-change-c77c6b49272420eea1d6324dd3016823)
    * [Fourth mass coral bleaching prompts UN emergency session at Colombia biodiversity summit](https://apnews.com/article/coral-un-bleaching-extinction-emergency-cop16-cali-colombia-ed4439fe10ac76a79443dbeab2c343c1)
    * ['All I can think about is hotter days.' Voter campaigns target Latinas worried about climate change](https://apnews.com/article/climate-change-election-2024-harris-trump-latinas-45b381be45eb4966636e13ffc4b3e025)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [McDonald's E. coli case count rises as federal officials inspect an onion grower](https://apnews.com/article/mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-quarter-pounder-a38666eaf2c38dccc99c00d72879928c)
    * [1st US case of bird flu in a pig raises concerns over potential human threat](https://apnews.com/article/bird-flu-pig-oregon-1f340a8f8c781e20478cbddabd2d9e18)
    * [Winter depression is real and there are many ways to fight back](https://apnews.com/article/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-depression-winter-370fdaf388a65e5b31400f61d97d0575)
    * [Teen fights kidney failure after eating McDonald's Quarter Pounders](https://apnews.com/article/mcdonalds-e-coli-food-poisoning-acb6d87f6182b42295d16625480525b0)
    * [People opt out of organ donation programs after reports of a man mistakenly declared dead](https://apnews.com/article/organ-donor-transplant-kentucky-8f42ad402445a91e981327abb009906c)
    * ['Obamacare' enrollment opens, as Republicans threaten the health insurance program used by millions](https://apnews.com/article/obamacare-affordable-care-act-harris-trump-kamala-9ac518845f3fd085bc68dcceed16b2c1)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Google Maps adds AI features to help users explore and navigate the world around them](https://apnews.com/article/google-maps-artificial-intelligence-entertainment-suggestions-bceb1ea762b3ac4a7a5a950fc4924756)
    * [New York semiconductor site picked for $825 million in funding](https://apnews.com/article/new-york-semiconductor-nanotech-lab-albany-42ee39316c32718c729e526354254724)
    * [Voting rights groups worry AI models are generating inaccurate and misleading responses in Spanish](https://apnews.com/article/ai-chatbots-chatgpt-falsehoods-spanish-latino-voters-d4ffabdc006a7c70eece3e28efa3de90)

    SECTIONS

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Ex-Disney worker accused of hacking computer menus to add profanities, errors](https://apnews.com/article/disney-arrest-florida-orlando-theme-parks-0c075b6ff23f3d57fe44be6ea1a85407)
    * [Google Maps adds AI features to help users explore and navigate the world around them](https://apnews.com/article/google-maps-artificial-intelligence-entertainment-suggestions-bceb1ea762b3ac4a7a5a950fc4924756)
    * [Garlands and treats for beloved dogs in Nepal’s annual Kukur Puja festival](https://apnews.com/article/nepal-dog-festival-photos-diwali-kukur-puja-cec969221447238e5d1e8610178d76aa)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Then & Now: How immigration reshaped the look of a Minnesota farm town](https://apnews.com/article/immigration-policy-integration-minnesota-history-churches-business-soccer-5385d18481c901ee1faeec19c16ebf6d)
    * [In Amharic, Karen and Spanish, worship is like home for migrants in heartland town](https://apnews.com/article/immigration-policy-integration-religion-churches-minnesota-ethiopia-karen-8b2fdb67d7d8f82c0ed6dd2d0da1cb6d)
    * [Takeaways from AP's report on how immigration transformed a Minnesota farm town](https://apnews.com/article/2024-election-immigration-policy-integration-minnesota-education-economy-019135a73205346a310eb1595da88d86)
    
    Newsletters
    
    [World of Faith
    
    Comprehensive global coverage of how religion shapes our world.](https://apnews.com/newsletters)

    TOP STORIES
    
    * [Preocupados defensores de derechos electorales en EEUU por información de IA incorrecta en español](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-hispanos-inteligencia-artificial-elecciones-desinformacion-15ed781dd93aa56b29fa3797837ea22c)
    * [España busca más víctimas tras unas inundaciones históricas que dejaron al menos 158 muertos](https://apnews.com/article/espana-valencia-inundaciones-muertos-tormenta-84dab89c07dbc6cd1a7b9823802737fe)
    * [Los votantes tienen claro el mensaje sobre las elecciones de EEUU: el destino del país está en juego](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-democracia-harris-trump-a58245ed4337c961615a1b043b54ffae)
    * [La lucha por el control del Senado en EEUU se decide al límite; los gastos rompen récords](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-senado-trump-harris-democratas-republicanos-cdaa79148a3f9086dbd9572d544c85f8)
    * [Encuesta de AP-NORC: Estadounidenses se sienten ansiosos y frustrados por campaña presidencial](https://apnews.com/article/eeuu-elecciones-harris-trump-ansiedad-sondeo-apnorc-9c23c5be8dac38493ac33c1e6114fa71)
    * [EEUU dice que unos 8.000 soldados norcoreanos están en región rusa de Kursk](https://apnews.com/article/ucrania-soldados-norcoreanos-rusia-da31fd01b1e1a6a1c72abc57fb7c3628)

*   
    
    The Associated Press is an independent global news organization dedicated to factual reporting. Founded in 1846, AP today remains the most trusted source of fast, accurate, unbiased news in all formats and the essential provider of the technology and services vital to the news business. More than half the world’s population sees AP journalism every day.

* The Associated Press
    
    * Cookie Settings

* More From AP News

    SECTIONS

* Copyright 2024 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved.

The Associated Press
====================

AP Privacy Policy

Last Updated: August 27, 2024  

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) applies to any and all information that The Associated Press and its affiliates (referred to together in this Privacy Policy as “AP,” “we,” “us,” “our,” and other similar pronouns) collect through those AP web sites and mobile applications that link to this Privacy Policy (together, the “Services”).  
  
We may revise or update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes to our privacy practices. We will notify you of any changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the revised or updated Privacy Policy and its “Last Updated” date on the Services. If a revision or modification is material, we may also provide you notification via email (as applicable) or via the web site. Your continued use of the Services after the “Last Updated” date constitutes your acceptance of and agreement to the Privacy Policy, including its revisions and updates. You should periodically read this Privacy Policy to learn of any revisions or updates. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us, or that we may obtain, where a separate privacy policy is provided.  

**Table of Contents**
---------------------

1. [What Personal Information May We Collect?](#personal-information)  
    1. User-Provided Information
    2. Automatically Collected Information
    3. Information Received from Third Parties
    4. Information You Provide About Third Parties
    5. Sensitive Personal Information
2. [How May We Use Your Personal Information?](#how-may-we-use-your-personal-information)
3. [With Whom Do We Share Personal Information We Collect?](#with-whom-do-we-share-personal-information-we-collect)
4. [How Do We Secure Your Personal Information?](#personal)
5. [Cookies Policy](#cookies): How Do the Services Use Cookies and Other  
      
    Types Tracking Technologies?  
      
    Type of Tracking Technologies  
      
    How We May Use Tracking Technologies  
      
    How You Can Manage Tracking Technologies  
    
6. [Links and Connections to Third-Party Services and Sites](#third-party)  
      
    Social Networks  
      
    Third-Party Web Sites and Content  

    Co-Sponsored Content  
      
    Third-Party Analytics Providers  
      
    Third-Party Ad Servers and Networks  
    
7. [Do Not Track Disclosures](#do-not-track)
8. [Opt Out of E-mail Marketing](#opt-out)
9. [Your Personal Information Rights and Choices](#personal-information)  
      
    1. Notice to California Residents
    2. US Residents
    3. Residents Outside the US
    4. Ad Blocking Recovery
10. [What Is Our Legal Basis for Use of Your Personal Information](#legal-basis)
11. [Children’s Privacy](#children-s-privacy)
12. [Data Retention](#data-retention)
13. [Contact Us](#contact-us)  

    \_

**1\. What Personal Information May We Collect?**
-------------------------------------------------

During your use of the Services (whether as a registered or unregistered user), you may provide us with information that relates to, describes, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to you (together, “Personal Information”).  
  
Personal Information may be collected directly from you, such as when you contact us via customer support, make advertisement inquiries, register for an account, or sign up for marketing emails. Personal Information may also be collected automatically, through your use of the Services or obtained from third parties.  
  
**_Personal Information collected may include:_**  

* **_User-Provided Information_**  
    * **Contact Information,** including your name, e-mail address, phone number, and address.
    * **Account Information,** including your name, email address, and password.
    * **Donation Information**, including your name, country, postal code, and donation amount. You may be required to provide financial or bank information prior to making a donation. Please note, we do not store financial and bank information; such information is processed and stored by our payment processor, Stripe. For more information on Stripe’s privacy practices, please visit: [https://stripe.com/privacy](https://stripe.com/privacy).
    * **User-Generated Content and Feedback**, including any Information, content, or comments that you submit to us, such as comments, photos, videos, audio, and text, whether submitted through online forms or social media platforms, by email, by phone, by mail, in surveys, or otherwise.
* **_Automatically Collected Information_**  
    * **Internet and Service Usage Information, Device Information and Identifiers,** including your IP address (which we may associate with your domain name or that of your Internet access provider or wireless carrier, and your location); unique ID number associated with your device; other unique identifiers such as advertising identifiers; web browser and operating system information; language of your device; wireless connections you are using; referring page that linked you to us; your activities, including browsing and transaction history; Pages, content, and ads you view or click on during your use of the Services, and when and for how long you do so; the next web site you visit after leaving our web site; and search terms you enter on the Services or a referral site. In addition, we may deploy tracking technologies through the Services to collect additional information about your use of the Services, as set out in the “Cookies and other tracking technologies” section of this Privacy Policy.
    * **Location Data**, including geographic location of your mobile device (a “Mobile Service”) if you have consented to location services generally through your device’s settings or accepted our request for geolocation access. Your device location may be transmitted to us whenever a Mobile Service is running (even if you are not actively using the Mobile Service or it is running in the background on your device). Your device may continue to transmit its location to us until you change your device settings. If you set your device not to transmit location information to us, certain features of the Services may not be available or their functions may be limited. For example, you will have to manually enter a location when conducting a search.
* **_Information Received from Third Parties_**  
    * **Information from Public and Commercial Sources.** In some instances, we may receive Personal Information and/or anonymous data about you from other parties, such as our affiliates, business partners, service providers, and other third parties. That information may be obtained online, offline, or through publicly available resources. We may combine this information with the information you provide and other data we already have about you.
    * **Social Media Information.** We may receive information about you from social media platforms when you interact with us on those platforms or access our social media content. Please note that the information we may receive from those third parties (such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Instagram, TikTok, and Youtube) is governed by the privacy settings, policies and/or procedures of the applicable platform, and we strongly encourage you to review them before submitting any information using each social media platform.
* **_Information You Provide About Third Parties_**  
    * Some of the Services allow you to provide us with Personal Information relating to other parties. For example, our donation functionality may allow you to share a donation link with family and friends by providing us access to Personal Information such as names, email addresses, or phone numbers of your family and friends (together, “Third-Party Data”).
    * If you use any feature of the Services that allows you to submit Third-Party Data to the Services or otherwise permits the Services to automatically access Third-Party Data in your possession, you acknowledge, represent, and agree that: (a) you have the authority of the relevant third party for us to access and use the relevant Third-Party Data; and (b) you have notified these other parties and informed them how their information is collected and used by us to provide the Services. We reserve the right to identify you as the person who has made the referral in any messages that are sent to these third parties.
    * We use Third-Party Data to (a) contact such third party using the Third-Party Data provided, and/or (b) provide you with an editable template message designed to facilitate communication between you and such party through the Services. We may also send reminders or related messages to you and to third parties on your behalf from time to time, as and where permitted by applicable law.
* **_Sensitive Personal Information_**_._ We generally do not collect or process Sensitive Personal Information. When you make a donation, you may be required to provide financial or bank information prior to making the donation. Please note, we do not store financial and bank information; such information is processed and stored by our payment processor, Stripe. For more information on Stripe’s privacy practices, please visit: [https://stripe.com/privacy](https://stripe.com/privacy).

\_

**2\. How May We Use Your Personal Information?**
-------------------------------------------------

We and/or our service providers may use the Personal Information we collect from or about you to perform the following functions:  

* **Providing the Services**. We may use your Personal Information to provide the Services and any other services you may request from us.
* **Monitoring the Services**. We collect your Personal Information for monitoring purposes to help us diagnose problems with our servers, administer and troubleshoot the Services, calculate usage levels, analyze industry standards, and analyze transactions, trends, and statistics regarding the use of the Services.
* **Facilitating Donations**. We collect your Personal Information to facilitate donations made to us via the Services.
* **Responding to Inquiries and Fulfilling Requests**. We may use your Personal Information to respond to your inquiries and to fulfill your requests for information.
* **Communicating with You**. We may use your Personal Information to send you marketing information about the Services, special promotions, and other items that may be of interest to you. We may also contact you on behalf of our third-party business partners about particular offerings of theirs that may be of interest to you.
* **Improving the Services**. We may use your Personal Information to make the Services more stable and user-friendly, to analyze service issues, improve the design and content of the Services, analyze how the Services are used, offer new services, and to develop new Services and programs relating to the Services.
* **Personalizing the Services**. We may use your Personal Information to personalize the Services based on your usage data, interests, and history with us. We may also localize the content and articles that are displayed to you based on your geographical location.
* **Advertising and Marketing to You**. We may use your Personal Information to tailor ads displayed to you in the Services and elsewhere.
* **Providing Customer Service**. We may use your Personal Information when contacting you regarding customer service or in response when you provide feedback. We may also use your information to send administrative emails regarding the Services or to inform you of any changes to this Privacy Policy, our Terms, or our third-party partner’s Terms.
* **Supporting Business Operations**. We may use your Personal Information (both on an individual basis and in aggregate) to support our internal and business operations, including internal and external audits, market research, analytics, security, assessment of your level of interest in and use of the Services, e-mails, and other messaging campaigns.
* **Enforcing Agreements**. We may use your Personal Information to enforce separate agreements between you and us, to enforce this Privacy Policy, our Terms, or our third-party partner’s Terms, or in connection with a transaction with a similar effect.
* **Safety and Security.** We may use your Personal Information to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud or security issues, and to protect against harm to our, your, or third parties’ rights, property, or safety.
* **Fulfilling Other Purposes**. We may use your Personal Information to fulfill: (a) any other purpose for which you provide it; (b) any legal or regulatory requirements and any of our internal policies; (c) other purposes disclosed at the time of collection; (d) any other purpose with your consent; and (e) any other purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy  
    
    \_

**3\. With Whom Do We Share Personal Information We Collect?**
--------------------------------------------------------------

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, share, rent, or otherwise disclose your Personal Information that we collect from the Services to any third parties for monetary or other valuable consideration, unless stated below or with your consent:  

* **Subsidiaries and Affiliates.** We may disclose Personal Information about you to our subsidiaries and affiliates.
* **Service Providers and Contractors**. To help us provide the Services, we may share your Personal Information with our service providers, contractors, and other third parties we use to support our business and who will safeguard your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Such third parties may help us with providing customer service, maintaining and analyzing data, and sending customer communications on our behalf.
* **Marketing Partners**. We may share your Personal Information with entities that perform marketing and/or data aggregation services on our behalf, or with whom we have joint marketing arrangements.
* **Advertising Partners.** We may share your Personal Information with third-party advertising partners, including but not limited to Google Display Advertising and Remarketing services. These advertising partners may use first- and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past visits to the Services. These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other services) for purposes of delivering personalized advertisements to you when you visit digital properties within their networks, commonly referred to as “interest-based advertising.”
* **Analytics Partners**. We may use analytics-based technologies to assist with personalization, advertising, and marketing. These technologies may capture how you interact with the Services through behavioral metrics, heatmaps, and session replay to improve and market our products and services.
* **Payment Processors**. We may disclose certain Personal Information to financial institutions as necessary for the Services.
* **Authorized Representatives.** If another individual is managing your account with us or your email account that the Services connect to on your behalf (for example, a spouse managing the account of the other spouse), as authorized by you or as a personal representative under applicable law, that person may view all Personal Information about you on the Services.
* **In the Event of Merger, Sale, Divestitures, or Change of Control.** We reserve the right to transfer Personal Information to a buyer or other successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of us or substantially all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which Personal Information held by us about you is among the assets transferred.
* **With Your Consent.** We may share your information for other purposes pursuant to your consent or at your direction.
* **Other Disclosures.** We may disclose your Personal Information if we have a good faith belief that disclosure of such information is helpful or reasonably necessary to: (i) conform to legal requirements and comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including responding to any government, law enforcement, or regulatory request; (ii) enforce the Terms of Use, other agreements, including between you and us, and any other documents included or referenced in the Terms of Use (all of which are incorporated into and made a part of this Privacy Policy by reference); (iii) fulfill the purpose for which you provide the Personal Information; (iv) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud or security issues; or (v) protect against harm to our, your, or third parties’ rights, property, or safety.
* **Non-Personally Identifiable Information**. We may analyze your information in aggregate form to operate, maintain, manage, and improve the Services. We may share non-personally identifiable information about usage of the Services (including aggregate data) with third parties, including our affiliates, agents, and business partners, for their own use, in a de-identified form.
* **Publicly Posted Information.** If you voluntarily post Personal Information to public areas of the Services, that information may be available to other Service users.  
    
    \_

**4\. How Do We Secure Your Personal Information?**
---------------------------------------------------

We use commercially reasonable technical, administrative, and physical security measures designed to protect Personal Information collected via the Services.  
  
We cannot guarantee that any information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from unauthorized access or use (e.g., by hackers). You use the Services, and send us information, at your own risk.  
  
If you create an account on the Services, you are responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your account password, and you shall be responsible for any activity, including disclosure of your Personal Information, that occurs using your account credentials, whether or not you authorized such activity. Please notify us of any unauthorized use of your password or account or any other breach of security.  

\_

**5\. Cookies Policy: How Do the Services Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies?**
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

We, and/or our service providers or partners on our behalf, may use tracking technologies, which may run on your device and/or browser when you use the Services. These technologies enable us to assign a unique number to your computer or device and to relate information about your use of the Services and other information about you, including Personal Information. These technologies also enable us to recognize you when you access our Services using different web browsers or devices.  
  
**_Types of Tracking Technologies:_** These tracking technologies may include:  

* **Cookies.** These are small pieces of text that are provided by most web sites and stored by your web browser on the computer, phone, or other device that you are using. Cookies serve many purposes, such as helping a web site remember your preferences, learning which areas of a web site are useful and which areas need improvement, and providing you with targeted advertisements or personalized content. Sometimes, cookies are enabled when pixels (see below) are placed on a web site. Cookies can be first-party or third-party. A first-party cookie is one that you receive directly from The Associated Press when visiting our Services. A third-party cookie is one that you receive from another party. Please note, we do not control what third parties do on other web sites. We may work with certain third-party providers to permit their cookies to function through our Services so we can learn more about your web experience on our Services and better personalize our Services for you.
* **Pixels.** Also called web beacons, clear GIFs, and tags, pixels are one-pixel transparent images that are located on web pages or messages. Pixels track whether you have opened web pages or messages. They enable web sites to read and place cookies.
* **Software Development Kits (SDKs).** SDKs are pieces of code provided by our digital vendors (such as third-party advertising companies, ad networks, and analytics providers) that may be in our mobile app to collect and analyze certain device and user data.
* **JavaScript.** This is a programming language that can be used to write trackers that, when embedded into a page, allow us to measure how you interact with our web site and other web sites.
* **Device Identifiers.** These are identifiers that are stored directly on a device and are unique to that specific device.

**_How We May Use Tracking Technologies:_** Circumstances in which we may deploy tracking technologies include:  

* We may use cookies or local shared objects, such as “Flash cookies.” Cookies are small packets of data that a web site stores on your computer’s or mobile device’s hard drive (or other storage medium) so that your computer will “remember” information about your visit. We use both first- and third-party session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our Services; a session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time or until you delete them. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your web browser’s “help” file. To the extent we provide a log-in portal or related feature on our Services, persistent cookies can be used to store your passwords so that you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our visitors to personalize the experience on our Services. Similar to many other web sites, if you have enabled cookies in your browser, we, independently and through enabled third-party tools and programs, may collect certain technical information using cookies, such as originating IP address, browser type, browser language, how a user got to the Service (i.e., the URL of the last web site you visited), the next web site the user visits, what pages are visited, the length of each site visit, and the date and time of the user’s visit. This information helps us track trends and improve user experiences when using the Services.
* HTML5 may be used to store information on your computer or device about your Service usage activities. This information can be retrieved by us to determine how our Services are being used by our visitors, how our Services may be improved, and to customize our Services for our users.
* We may send instructions to your computer or device using JavaScript or other computer languages to gather the sorts of information described above and other details about your interactions with the Service.
* We use Meta Pixel and Google Pixel to understand how our web site, services, and products perform, how you use them, and to serve you with ads on third-party web sites and social networking sites. These pixels may collect certain limited information such as your IP address, browser/device type, and the pages you visit on our Services. This data is stored and processed by Meta and Google, as applicable. For information about how Meta may use this data, please visit Meta’s Privacy Policy at [https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policy/](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policy/). For information about how Google may use this data, please visit [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

**_How You Can Manage Tracking Technologies:_**   

* A cookie banner will be displayed to users of our Services who are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or the United Kingdom (“UK”), which will invite users to give their consent, where applicable, and will provide further options for the management of tracking technologies.
* For residents of certain countries and states, in Your Privacy Choices, you may choose not to allow certain types of tracking technologies (which may impact your experience of the Services). You can access Your Privacy Choices by going to our web site’s navigation menu (the three-line menu in the upper left corner of our web site), then scrolling down to and clicking on “Your Privacy Choices.”
* You can manage SDKs in your mobile app’s settings. If you choose to change your settings, you may find that certain functions and features will not work as intended on the Services.
* You can manage web site cookies in your browser settings. If you choose to change your settings, you may find that certain functions and features will not work as intended on the Services. All browser settings are **slightly** **different**, so to manage cookies, you should refer to the relevant settings within your browser. Please click below for detailed information on how to disable and delete cookies in some commonly used browsers:  
    * Mozilla Firefox: [https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/clear-cookies-and-site-data-firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/clear-cookies-and-site-data-firefox)
    * Microsoft Internet Explorer: [https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11)
    * Microsoft Edge: [https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/search?query=edge%20clear%20cookies%20and%20cache](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/search?query=edge%20clear%20cookies%20and%20cache)
    * Google Chrome: [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en)
    * Safari Mac: [https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-sfri11471/mac](https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-sfri11471/mac)
    * Safari iPhone, iPad, or iPod Touch: [https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265)  
        
        \_

**6\. Links and Connections to Third-Party Services ad Sites**
--------------------------------------------------------------

**_Social Networks._** We maintain a presence on social media and other external platforms, such as Facebook and Twitter. We may occasionally incorporate third-party social networking features into the Services. This Privacy Policy applies to our use of Personal Information you submit to us through those platforms, but please note that it does not apply to what those third-party platforms do with your Personal information.  
  
The Services may allow you to share Personal Information with us that you have already provided to a third-party social networking platform. For example, you may be able to create an account on the Services or log in to the Services using your Facebook account or other third-party credentials. If you do so, Personal Information or other data that you have provided to the third party may be made available to us by that third party subject to its own privacy policy, terms, and conditions. Privacy policies of social networks and other external platforms explain how those third parties use, protect, and share your information, including any information you share on those platforms from the Services, and we encourage you to read these privacy policies. The information we receive from these platforms may depend on your privacy settings.  
  
We may also include tools in the Services that allow you to share or publicly post content from the Services to your profile on a third-party social network. You may choose to share information about your activities on the Services with such third-party platforms and their users, including publishing your information about what content you may have viewed on the Services. If you visit the Services while logged into certain social media platforms, the social media platform may be able to identify your browser and associate the technical information provided by your web browser with other information that they have already collected about you, which may result in their ability to identify you. In addition, when you choose to share information about your activities on the Services with certain social media platforms, AP may send technical information about you to that platform as well as information about what content you are viewing.  
  
**_Third-Party Web Sites and Content._** The Services may allow access to third-party content and services, such as via links, banners, widgets, or advertisements that lead to third-party web sites (“Third-Party Web Sites”). We are not responsible for these other web sites or services. You acknowledge and agree that the privacy policies and terms of use posted by such Third-Party Web Sites (and not AP’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Use) will govern the collection and use of your information through them.  
  
For example:  

* The Services utilize YouTube’s API Services. When you engage YouTube’s content and services through our Services, [YouTube’s Terms of Service](https://www.youtube.com/t/terms) and [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy) controls shall apply.
* We use JW Player to serve video across the Services. Information about the data collected via the JW Player can be found in [JWP’s Privacy Policy](https://jwplayer.com/legal/privacy/).
* The Services may use Hearken’s services to learn more about users of our Services. Information about Hearken’s privacy practices can be found in [Hearken’s Privacy Policy](https://wearehearken.com/privacy-policies/).
* The Services may provide content from another content affiliate, Data Skrive. If you engage with that content, you will be subject to Data Skrive’s privacy policy found [here](https://dataskrive.com/privacy-policy/).

We encourage you to read the privacy statements of services visited through the Services or web sites visited after leaving the Services to learn about how your information is treated by others.  

\_

**_AP Buyline._** AP Buyline ([Personal Finance](https://apnews.com/buyline-personal-finance/), [Shopping](https://apnews.com/hub/shopping)) is an initiative designed to simplify complex consumer-made decisions by providing its audience with reliable evaluations and straightforward insights. The AP Buyline web site is hosted by Taboola.com Ltd., and [Taboola’s Privacy Policy](https://www.taboola.com/policies/privacy-policy) (available [here](https://www.taboola.com/policies/privacy-policy)) applies to your use of AP Buyline.  
  
**_Co-Sponsored Content._** The Services may contain certain co-sponsored content, and you may be requested to provide additional Personal Information to the co-sponsor of such content. The information practices of any third-party co-sponsors are governed by their own privacy policies and are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  
  
**_Third-Party Analytics Providers._** We use one or more third-party analytics services to evaluate your use of the Services by compiling reports on activity (based on their collection of information such as IP addresses, Internet service provider, browser type, operating system and language, referring and exit pages and URLs, data and time, amount of time spent on particular pages, what sections of the Services you visit, number of links clicked, search terms, and other similar usage data) and analyzing performance metrics. These third parties use cookies and other tracking technologies to help collect, analyze, and provide us with reports or other data. These third-party analytics services include:  

* **Google Analytics**. We use Google Analytics on the Services to help us analyze the traffic on the Services. For more information on Google Analytics’ processing of Personal Information, please see [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). You may opt out of the use of Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
* **Scorecard.** We use Scorecard to measure digital consumption behavior data, which may include information about online activities, and video streaming activities, among other activities, as part of its broad market research efforts. For more information regarding Scorecard’s privacy practices please visit [here](https://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx#sec5).
* **Parse.ly.** We use Parse.ly to assess content performance. For more information regarding Parse.ly’s privacy practices, please visit [here](https://wpvip.com/privacy/).
* **ComScore.** We use Comscore to assess the performance of our Servies. For information about ComScore’s privacy practices, please visit [here](https://www.comscore.com/About/Privacy-Policy).

For US Residents: By accessing and using the Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by these analytics providers in the manner and for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.  
  
For Residents Outside the US: A cookie banner will be displayed to users of our Services located outside the US, which will invite users to give their consent, where applicable, and will provide further options about the management of cookies.  
  
For more information on these third-party analytics providers, including how to opt out from certain data collection, please visit the web sites and opt out via each providers’ privacy policies. You may also take steps to opt out via the methods listed in this Privacy Policy. Please be advised that if you opt out of any third-party data collection, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Services.  
  
**_Third-Party Ad Servers and Networks._** We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Services. When you view an advertisement, whether or not you click on it, the advertiser, advertising technology companies, web analytics companies, and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and our business partners may collect some information from or about you. These companies may use information about your visits to the Services, the geographic location where your IP address indicates you are located, and other information about you to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These advertisements may appear in our Services and on other online properties or mobile applications. These companies may employ tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. We do not control any such tracking technologies employed by these third parties that may appear in our Services or other online properties or mobile applications. The information practices of these third parties are governed by their own privacy policies and are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  
  
For US Residents: By accessing and using the Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by these advertising providers in the manner and for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.  
  
For Residents Outside the US: A cookie banner will be displayed to users of the Services who are located outside the US, which will invite users to give their consent, where applicable, and will provide further options in respect of the management of cookies.  
  
**For more information about third-party advertisers:**  
  
For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt-Out Page available here.](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)  
  
To opt out of interest-based advertising by participating Digital Advertising Alliance members:  

* For US residents, please go to: [https://optout.aboutads.info/](https://optout.aboutads.info/)
* For Canadian residents, please go to: [https://youradchoices.ca/choices](https://youradchoices.ca/choices)
* For residents of the EU, Switzerland and the UK, please go to: [https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

You may also visit the web sites of the third parties set forth below. Please note that this list may be subject to change based on the campaigns that we run.  

* Connatix: [https://www.connatix.com/privacy-policy](https://www.connatix.com/privacy-policy)
* Taboola: [https://www.taboola.com/policies/privacy-policy](https://www.taboola.com/policies/privacy-policy) or Taboola’s Trust Center at: [https://help.taboola.com/hc/en-us/articles/360004904154-Taboola-s-Trust-Center](https://help.taboola.com/hc/en-us/articles/360004904154-Taboola-s-Trust-Center)
* Nativo: [https://www.nativo.com/about/adchoices](https://www.nativo.com/about/adchoices)
* Google Publisher Tags: [https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/7678538?hl=en](https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/7678538?hl=en)
* Google Ad Settings: [https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?ref=mac-hub&hl=en](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?ref=mac-hub&hl=en)
* Verve: [https://verve.com/privacy-policy/](https://verve.com/privacy-policy/)
* Smaato: [https://www.smaato.com/privacy/](https://www.smaato.com/privacy/)
* Wunderkind: [https://www.wunderkind.co/privacy/](https://www.wunderkind.co/privacy/)
* Pubmatic: [https://pubmatic.com/legal/opt-out/](https://pubmatic.com/legal/opt-out/)
* OpenX: [https://www.openx.com/privacy-center/privacy-policy/](https://www.openx.com/privacy-center/privacy-policy/)
* Sovrn: [https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/privacy-policy/](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/privacy-policy/)
* Comscore: [http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx) (to opt out of data collected by Comscore globally) or [https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) (to opt out of Comscore’s sharing for Internet-Based Advertising purposes)
* LiveIntent: [https://www.liveintent.com/services-privacy-policy/](https://www.liveintent.com/services-privacy-policy/)
* InMobi: [https://www.inmobi.com/privacy-policy](https://www.inmobi.com/privacy-policy)

In some instances, we collect data and work with third parties to show you personalized ads of behalf of our advertisers. For example:  

* LiveRamp. To opt out of LiveRamp, please visit [here](https://optout.liveramp.com/opt_out).
* Meta Pixel and Google Pixel. As detailed above (see Section 5 of this Privacy Policy), we use Meta Pixel and Google Pixel to better measure, optimize, and retarget our marketing campaigns. For information on Meta’s use of personalized ads, please visit [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217). For information on Google’s use of personalized ads, please visit [here](https://support.google.com/My-Ad-Center-Help/answer/12155656?hl=en&co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid#zippy=%2Cwhen-youre-signed-in-to-your-google-account).
* Cross-App Advertising on Mobile Apps. You can opt out of having your mobile device IDs used for certain types of interest-based mobile advertising (also called “cross-app advertising”), including by accessing the settings on your Apple or Android mobile device. For more detailed instructions on opting out of mobile device tracking, please visit [here](https://thenai.org/opt-out/mobile-opt-out/).

Please note that if you opt out of any third-party data collection described in this section, we may still suggest offerings (including content sponsored by third parties) to you on our Services based on your history or your account preferences.  

\_

**7\. Do Not Track Disclosures**
--------------------------------

Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” (“DNT”) signals to mobile applications with which the user communicates. We currently do not change our tracking practices (which are explained in more detail under “Service Usage Information” above) in response to DNT settings in your web browser.  

\_

**8\. Opt Out of E-mail Marketing**
-----------------------------------

You can opt out of our promotional e-mails by clicking the opt-out/unsubscribe link within the e-mail you receive. Please understand that it may take us a few days to process any opt-out request, and that even if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your relationship, activities, transactions, and communications with us.  

\_

**9\. Your Personal Information Rights and Choices**
----------------------------------------------------

**_A. Notice to California Residents_**  
  
The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (“CPRA”), provides California residents with certain rights regarding their personal information and requires businesses to provide residents with information about the collection and use of their personal information:  

* For information about opting out of the sale and sharing of personal information for targeted ads, please go to “Your Privacy Choices” in the web site menu in the upper left corner of the web site or footer of the web site.
* For information about accessing, correcting, or deleting personal information, go [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/32b3f960-c18a-4dad-96b3-28213a220bd8)
* For information about categories of personal information we may disclose, go to Section 3 “With Whom Do We Share Personal Information We Collect?”
* For information about our retention of your personal information, go to Section 12 “Data Retention.”
* To opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information, go [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/766ad301-0e47-4688-b35c-08a0bd369481)
* For information about the categories of personal information we collect and the purposes for which we use it, please see the table below:  
    
    |     |     |     |     |
    | --- | --- | --- | --- |
    | **_Categories of Personal Information\*_** | **_Examples of Personal Information\*_** | **_Source(s)_** | **_Purpose(s)\*\*_** |
    | Contact Information, Account Information | Name, email address, phone number, address, password | User Provided | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Monitoring the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Responding to Inquiries and Fulfilling Requests  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Communicating with You  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services.  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Providing Customer Service  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and Security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    | Donation Information\*\*\* | Name, country, postal code, donation amount, and financial or bank information (processed and stored by our payment processor, Stripe, [https://stripe.com/privacy](https://stripe.com/privacy)) | User Provided | Facilitating Donations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and Security |
    | User-Generated Content, Feedback | Information, content, or comments that you submit to us, such as comments, photos, videos, audio, and text, whether submitted through online forms or social media platforms, by email, by phone, by mail, in surveys, or otherwise. | User Provided | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Responding to Inquiries and Fulfilling Requests  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Communicating with You  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You Providing Customer Service  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and Security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    | Internet and Service Usage Information, Device Information and Identifiers | IP address (which we may associate with your domain name or that of your Internet access provider or wireless carrier, and your location); unique ID number associated with your device; other unique identifiers such as advertising identifiers; web browser and operating system information; language of your device; wireless connections you are using; referring page that linked you to us; your activities, including browsing and transaction history; Pages, content, and ads you view or click on during your use of the Services, and when and for how long you do so; the next web site you visit after leaving our web site; and search terms you enter on the Services or a referral site. | Automatically Collected | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Monitoring the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>   <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and Security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    | Location Data | Geographic location of your mobile device (a “Mobile Service”) if you have consented to location services generally through your device’s settings or accepted our request for geolocation access. | Automatically Collected | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Monitoring the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    | Information from Public and Commercial Sources | This information may be obtained online, offline, or through publicly available resources. We may combine this information with information you provide and other data we already have about you. | Provided by Third Parties (such as our affiliates, business partners, service providers, and other third parties) | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Monitoring the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    | Social Media Information | The information we may receive from these third parties is governed by the privacy settings, policies and/or procedures of the applicable platforms. | Provided by Third Parties (social media platforms when you interact with us on those platforms or access our social media content) | Providing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Monitoring the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Improving the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Personalizing the Services  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Advertising and Marketing to You Supporting Business Operations  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Enforcing Agreements  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Safety and security  <br>  <br>  <br>  <br>Fulfilling Other Purposes |
    
    \* For additional information about the categories of personal information we collect, go to Section 1 “What Personal Information May We Collect?”  

    \*\* For additional information about the purposes for which we collect personal information, go to Section 2 “How May We Use Your Personal Information?”  

    \*\*\* Financial and bank information required when making donations may be considered “sensitive” under certain laws, and we process this information in accordance with applicable laws.

California’s Shine the Light Law: Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to obtain certain information about the types of Personal Information that companies with whom they have an established business relationship (and that are not otherwise exempt) have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, including the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the types of services or products marketed by those third parties. If you wish to submit a request pursuant to Section 1798.83, go [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/766ad301-0e47-4688-b35c-08a0bd369481).  
  
**_B. US Residents_**  
Residents of certain US States have state-law rights regarding use of their Personal Information. While some of these laws may not apply to not-for-profit organizations, we permit residents of these states to exercise similar control over their Personal Information. If you are a resident of a US state that does not currently have applicable laws in effect, you may not be able to make these privacy choices at this time, but your ability to do so may change as data privacy laws change.  

**Opt Out of Sale of Personal Information and Sharing/Processing for Targeted Ads. _For California, Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Utah, and Virginia Residents Only._**  
  
**Tracking Technologies.**  
To opt out of the sale or sharing/processing of your Personal Information for targeted ads for the site/app on your browser/device via tracking technologies, go to “Your Privacy Choices” on our web site, which you can access by going to the navigation menu (upper left corner of our web site), then scrolling down to and clicking on “Your Privacy Choices.” When opt-out preference signals are detected, they will be honored. As you make your privacy choices, please keep in mind the following:  

* If you decide not to allow the sale of Personal Information or sharing/processing of Personal Information for targeted ads, you will continue to see ads, but they may be less relevant or based only on information that we collect directly from your use of the Services.
* Choices related to tracking technologies (including cookies and device identifiers) are specific to the site/app on the browser/device where you are making the selection, meaning that you must make Your Privacy Choices selections on each site/app on each browser/device you use to access our web site.
* You must renew your selections for Your Privacy Choices each time you clear your cookies.

**Name, Email, and Associated Personal Information (“Do Not Sell or Share/Process My Personal Information for Targeted Ads”).** We do not sell your Personal Information in exchange for monetary consideration. Our use of certain technologies described in this Privacy Policy may be interpreted as sharing your Personal Information for targeted advertising. You can opt out of the use of your name, email, and other associated Personal Information for targeted advertising activities by completing and submitting our [Do Not Sell or Share/Process My Personal Info Form](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/766ad301-0e47-4688-b35c-08a0bd369481).  
  
**Access, Correct, or Delete Personal Information. _For California, Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Utah, and Virginia Residents Only._**  
Residents of states with relevant laws may make the following requests regarding use of Personal Information:  

* **Request to Access Information.** You may request that we confirm whether we are collecting or processing your Personal Information. Depending on relevant law, you may ask us to provide access to certain information we hold about you, in some cases in a portable format, if technically feasible
* **Request to Delete Information**. You may request that we delete your Personal Information that we have collected from you. We will honor your request to the extent we are able to, but please not that we may have reason to deny or limit your request, such as a legal obligation to retain information or to provide goods or services that you have requested.
* **Request to Correct Personal Information**. You may request that we maintain accurate Personal Information about you and correct any inaccuracies in your Personal Information that we have collected from you, subject to exceptions within the law.
* **Request to Limit Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information**. California law permits residents to limit the use or disclosure of their “Sensitive Personal Information” as defined under relevant law. We generally do not collect or process Sensitive Personal Information. In the event we do process Sensitive Personal Information, we will not use or disclose it other than for disclosed and permitted business purposes as allowed under relevant law.

To make a request to access, correct, or delete your Personal Information, you may make this request [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/32b3f960-c18a-4dad-96b3-28213a220bd8).  
  
**_Authorized Agent_.** Depending on relevant law, you may authorize another person (your “agent”) to submit a request on your behalf.  
  
**_Processing Requests._** Once you submit your request, we will contact you with instructions for how to verify the request. We strive to complete verified requests as soon as reasonably practicable and consistent with relevant law. Please note that it may take additional time to verify and fulfill agent-submitted requests. Also note that many of the above requests are subject to exceptions and limitations.  
  
**_Nondiscrimination._** We will not discriminate against (as defined in relevant laws) you because you exercise any of your privacy rights or choices contained in this Privacy Policy.  
  
**_C. Residents Outside the US_**  
  
Residents of some countries outside the US, such as the EEA and the UK, have the rights, in certain circumstances, to: (i) require us to delete your Personal Information, (ii) require us to restrict processing of your Personal Information (also referred to as Personal Data) (for example, if you contest the accuracy of that information), (iii) receive a copy of the Personal Information you provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or instruct us to transmit that data to a third party, and (iv) object to our continued processing of your Personal Information, for direct marketing (including profiling) or other purposes. If you reside in one of these countries, you can exercise these rights [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/32b3f960-c18a-4dad-96b3-28213a220bd8).  
  
You may object to Personal Information processed pursuant to our legitimate interest (see Section 10 for information about our legitimate interest as a legal basis). In such case, we will no longer process your Personal Information unless we can demonstrate appropriate, overriding legitimate grounds for the processing or if needed for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims. You may also object at any time to processing of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes. You may make these objections [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/9efcd77d-fbf7-40b0-a4b6-8fe108d3d374/32b3f960-c18a-4dad-96b3-28213a220bd8).  
  
You may also object at any time to processing of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes by clicking “Opt Out” or “Unsubscribe” within an automated marketing email. In such case, your Personal Information will no longer be used for that purpose.  
  
**D. Ad Blocking Recovery**  
  
We use data to support digital advertising activities on our Services that help us bring AP’s fast, accurate and unbiased news to you at no cost. We respect our users’ desire to limit the ads they receive. For instance, you may be able to limit your receipt of targeted ads (see above in Section 9). We also want you to be aware that, if you use an adblocker, the adblocker’s default settings could include your provision of consent to ads that meet certain standards, which may include some of the ads we serve through our Services. To change that setting, please go to your adblocker's settings.  

\_

**10\. What Is Our Legal Basis for Use of Your Personal Information?**
----------------------------------------------------------------------

The laws of some jurisdictions, such as the EEA and the UK, require us to tell you about the legal basis for using, sharing, or disclosing your Personal Information. To the extent those laws apply, we may rely on the following legal bases:  

* **Consent** - The consent you provide to us at the point of collection of your Personal Information. Where we rely on this basis, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time (see Your Personal Information Rights and Choices in Section 9).  
    
* **Contract** \- The performance of a contract we have with you.  
    
* **Legal Obligation** \- The compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject.  
    
* **Legitimate Interest** – Where use of your Personal Information is necessary for our or third parties’ legitimate interests and where the use is not outweighed by your rights and interests. Legitimate interests include: providing the Services; improving the Services and developing new ones; recognizing and better understanding our users; conducting security and fraud-prevention activities; marketing and promoting our content and Services; conducting compliance and risk-management activities; ensuring the network and information security of our systems.

\_

**11\. Children’s Privacy**
---------------------------

We care about protecting the privacy of children. You must be at least eighteen (18) years of age to submit any User Content or personal information on or through the Services, register for an account, or purchase any goods or services. If you are between the ages of thirteen (13) and 18, you may view the Services with the consent of your parent or legal guardian, provided that you do not engage in any of the activities prohibited in the prior sentence. We do not knowingly collect personal information of individuals under the age of 18. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under 18, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 18 has provided personal information to us, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://apnews.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.  

\_

**12\. Data Retention**
-----------------------

We will retain your personal information while you have an account with us. If you do not have an account with us, or if your account terminates for any reason, we will retain your personal information for as long as we have a legitimate need to retain it. Thereafter, we will either delete your personal information or de-identify it so that it is anonymous and not attributed to your identity.  

\_

**13\. Contact Us**
-------------------

To submit requests to Opt Out of Sale and Sharing/Processing of Personal Information for Targeted Ads and Requests to Access, Correct, or Delete Personal Information, whether for yourself or as an authorized agent, please follow the instructions provided in the “Your Personal Information Rights and Choices” section of this Privacy Policy. Alternatively, you may contact us by phone at 212.621.1599.  
  
If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy practices, you may contact us as follows:  

* By email: [\[email protected\]](https://apnews.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
    
* New York Office: The Associated Press, 200 Liberty Street, New York, NY 10281, 212.621.1500  
    
* London Office: The Associated Press Television News Limited, The Interchange, Oval Road, Camden Lock, London, NW1 7DZ, (44-20) 7482-7400

We aim to resolve any query or concern you may raise about our use of your information. Please note that individuals located in the EEA or the UK have the right to lodge a complaint with an applicable supervisory authority.

The Associated Press is an independent global news organization dedicated to factual reporting. Founded in 1846, AP today remains the most trusted source of fast, accurate, unbiased news in all formats and the essential provider of the technology and services vital to the news business. More than half the world’s population sees AP journalism every day.

* The Associated Press
    
    * Cookie Settings
    
* More From AP News

Copyright 2024 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved.
